Emmanuel Senft

Curriculum Vitae

CONTACT

Address Plymouth University, A216 Portland Square

Drake Circus, Plymouth, PL4 8AA

United Kingdom

Email emmanuel.senft@plymouth.ac.uk

Phone +44 (0)7751 689105

Website https://emmanuel-senft.github.io/index.html

Scholar https://scholar.google.co.uk/citations?user=Yw1tGf4AAAAJ&hl=en

RESEARCH STATEMENT

Robots I research and develop Interactive Machine Learning systems for robots interacting Learning to socially with humans. My current research is centred around SPARC (Supervised Interact Progressively Autonomous Robot Competencies), a framework of interaction allowing humans to teach robots to interact with humans in the real world. My research lies at the intersection between social Human-Robot Interaction, Interactive Machine Learning and Learning from Demonstrations.

EDUCATION

- 2014-2018 PhD, Plymouth University, Plymouth, UK, Obtained in November 2018. Supervisory team: Professor Tony Belpaeme, Dr. Paul Baxter and Dr Séverin Lemaignan
- 2011–2013 Master of Science in Robotic and Autonomous Systems, Swiss Federal Institute of Technology Lausanne (EPFL), Lausanne, Switzerland, Grade 5.5/6. With Minor in Area and Cultural Studies.
- 2008–2011 Bachelor of Science in Microengineering, Swiss Federal Institute of Technology Lausanne (EPFL), Lausanne, Switzerland, Grade 5.29/6.

PHD THESIS

Title Teaching Robots Social Autonomy From In Situ Human Supervision

link https://github.com/emmanuel-senft/thesis/blob/master/ES%20Thesis. pdf

MASTER THESIS

Title Hybrid Optimisation with Roombots (Maximum possible grade obtained: 6/6)

SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

- 2018 The PInSoRo Dataset: Supporting the Data-Driven Study of Child-Child and Child-Robot Social Dynamics S. Lemaignan, C. Edmunds, E. Senft, T. Belpaeme PLOS ONE, 2018.
- 2017 Supervised Autonomy for Online Learning in Human-Robot Interaction E. Senft, P. Baxter, J. Kennedy, S. Lemaignan and T. Belpaeme Pattern Recognition Letters, 2017.
 - How to Build a Supervised Autonomous System for Robot-Enhanced Therapy for Children with Autism Spectrum Disorder P.G. Esteban, ..., E. Senft, ..., T.Ziemke Paladyn, Journal of Behavioral Robotics. De Gruyter Open, 2017.
- 2016 From Characterising Three Years of HRI to Methodology and Reporting Recommendations P. Baxter, J. Kennedy, E. Senft, S. Lemaignan and T. Belpaeme Proc. 11th ACM/IEEE International Conference on Human-Robot Interaction (alt.HRI) (HRI), New Zealand, Christchurch, March 2016.
 - **Social Robot Tutoring for Child Second Language Learning** J. Kennedy, P. Baxter, **E. Senft** and T. Belpaeme Proc. 11th ACM/IEEE International Conference on Human-Robot Interaction (HRI), New Zealand, Christchurch, March 2016.
- 2015 SPARC: Supervised Progressively Autonomous Robot Competencies E. Senft, P. Baxter, J. Kennedy and T. Belpaeme. Proc. 7th International Conference of Social Robotics (ICSR), Paris, France, October 2015.
- Complete list https://emmanuel-senft.github.io/publication.html with pdf

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

- 2019 **PC Member**, International Conference on Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems (AAMAS).
- 2017-2018 PC Chair, AAAI Fall Symposium on AI for HRI (AI-HRI).
- since 2015 **Reviewer**, Scientific Reports, JIST, SORO, ICRA, MECH, HAI, JHRI, IS, HRI, ICSR, HUMANOID, RO-MAN....
- 2015-2017 **Demonstrator**, *ROCO 318 Mobile and Humanoid Robots*, Plymouth University, UK.
 - Leading practical work on bipedal gait design and control for 3rd year students.
 - 2014 **Construction Assistant**, *Biorobotic Lab*, *EPFL*, Lausanne, Switzerland, Two months.
 - Development of a controller using a camera and an IMU as inputs to allow autonomous docking on a passive grid using Roombots.
- 2012–2013 **Internship**, *EPFL+ECAL Lab*, Lausanne, Switzerland, Four months.

 Development of a driver for a multitouch tactile wall for a permanent interactive installation at the Red Cross Museum, Geneva, Switzerland.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Advanced Python, ROS, QML, C++, Machine Learning (Neural Networks and Reinforcement

Learning), Robotics, Nao, Human-Robot Interaction, Study Design, Academic

Writing

Intermediate Solidworks, ProEngineer, MatLab, C, JAVA, Pepper and YARP

Basic Robot Simulator (Webots) and Assembly

Languages

French Mother tongue

English Advanced Conversationally fluent and technical

German Basic Level A2

Italian Elementary Level A1

Mandarin Elementary Level A1

OTHER EXPERIENCE

2016-2017 **Comittee member**, *Karate-UPSU*, Plymouth University, UK.

Treasurer for the university karate club.

2014-2018 **Member**, A+E, Plymouth University, UK.

Mountaineering, climbing and caving student club.

2014-2018 Member, Karate-UPSU, Plymouth University, UK.

Karate student club.

2010-2013 Comittee member, Jdr-Poly, EPFL.

Association for the promotion of Role Playing Games and Board Games on the campus.

2007-2013 Scout Team Leader, Eclaireuses et Eclaireurs Unionistes de France, Douvaine,

France.

Team management and leadership, organisation of events with 8-12 or 12-16 years old children with legal responsibility, member from 1998 to 2014.

2008-2012 **Member**, *Robopoly*, EPFL.

Robotic Association.